ALLEN TAN

 \P San Diego, CA \red 619-890-9266 \red algtan.dev@gmail.com

Summary

Driven software engineer, changing careers after 6+ years as a mechanical engineer. Enjoy the challenge of finding solutions to complex problems by breaking them down into manageable pieces.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Ruby, HTML/CSS, SQL

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Express, Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap Other: Git, Chai, RSpec, CouchDB (noSQL)

Relevant Experience

Edge May 2021 – Present

 $Software\ Engineer\ Intern$

San Diego, CA

- Built the backend of a server that maintains information on the minimum amount required for a cryptocurrency swap, using Node, Express, and CouchDB (noSQL)
- Developed a snack bar web application in React that fetches cryptocurrency exchange rates using promises, and shows a QR code for payment when the user selects a currency
- Reviewed code on PRs (pull requests) for Edge's fee tracker and theme server
- Maintained clean Git commit history for contributions to open-source codebase by utilizing rebase and cherry-pick
- Fixed bugs and added functionality to existing internal tools, including the reports server and logs server
- Created unit tests using Chai and Mocha for utility functions that helped retrieve and insert swap provider information into a CouchDB database

Projects

Edge Swap Server | TypeScript, Node, Express, CouchDB

Aug 2021

- Built a server that maintains the swap information for multiple providers and cryptocurrencies
- Created a helper function that utilizes the binary search algorithm to find the minimum amount
- Wrote middleware in Express that gets the latest minimum amount information from the database

Edge Snack Bar | TypeScript, React

Jun 2021

- Developed an application to generate payment QR codes for Edge's in-office snack bar
- Created a helper function to asynchronously fetch exchange rate data for 17+ cryptocurrencies using promises
- Utilized React and CSS to make a responsive web application

Pokedeck | JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, React, RSpec, Enzyme

Apr 2021

- Developed a Pokemon Trading Card Game where users compete to have the most valuable collection
- Designed back end API that allows users to claim their initial booster pack of 10 cards, claim their card that becomes available after 24 hours, and view their ranking
- Produced unit tests for the back end controllers using RSpec, and for the front end React components using Enzyme

Other Experience

Solar Turbines (via Volt)

Jan 2017 - Dec 2020

Senior Engineer (NPI Combustion Mechanical Design)

San Diego, CA

• Developed dozens of new combustion components, including fuel injectors, liners, and fuel systems, using computer-aided design (CAD) and multiphysics simulation software

Mikroscan Technologies, Inc

Jan 2015 – Jan 2017

Mechanical Design Engineer

Carlsbad, CA

• Managed multiple aspects of the SL5 hardware, including design, procurement, and inventory management

Education

San Diego State University

2012 - 2015

Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering

San Diego, CA

University of California, San Diego

2007 - 2012

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

La Jolla, CA